# Neha Bharambe

Email: neha.bharambe@gmail.com

**Phone**: +1 (647) 250-4633

*LinkedIn*: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/neha-bharambe">https://www.linkedin.com/in/neha-bharambe</a>

*GitHub*: <a href="https://github.com/nehabharambe">https://github.com/nehabharambe</a> *Visa Status:* Canadian Permanent Resident

Data Scientist experienced in data collecting and analyzing datasets in order to derive successful business solutions. Proficient knowledge in statistics and mathematics. Working experience of data visualization tools like Tableau and D3.js. Around 4 years of experience working as a software developer. Strong problem solving and analytical skills.

#### SKILLS

Programming Skills Python, R, JavaScript, VBA for excel, D3, HTML

Databases Oracle, SQL, MySQL, MongoDB

Data Visualization Tableau, D3.js

Machine Learning Skills Regression, Classification, Natural language processing

### **EXPERIENCE**

## City of Jersey City

**Data Scientist** 

- Modernize City's data collection processes to make it Smart City.
- Build strategies for Data mining to deliver insightful results.
- Analyze City's data using machine learning techniques to have action driven solution to the problem.
- Manage City's Open data portal and data stories
- Analyzed affordable housing options in Jersey City and reviewed RFP for Affordable Housing Portal
- Created various public facing tableau visualizations to showcase key metrics and statistics for multiple City's project - Composting in Jersey City, Environmental Impact Initiatives, Streets resurfaced from 2008 <a href="https://public.tableau.com/profile/jersey.city#!/">https://public.tableau.com/profile/jersey.city#!/</a>
- Analyze COVID-19 data of Jersey City and its impact.
- Built a tableau visualization on COVID-19 patients in Jersey City to provide up to date information to residents

https://bit.ly/covidjc

City of Jersey CityJersey City NJ USAData Science InternFeb 2019 – Apr 2019

- Analyzed and developed a dashboard on Parking dataset
- Analyzed parking violations dataset to determine which area needs enforcement at what time of day.

### **Deloitte Consulting LLP**

Consultant

Mumbai MH, India Jun 2016 – Nov 2016

- Worked as Workday Integration Consultant.
- Ensure Defect Free delivery and adhering to software development Life cycle.

### Tata Consultancy Services Limited

System Engineer

Mumbai MH, India Feb 2013 – May 2016

- Worked as PeopleSoft Technical/Functional Consultant.
- Managed team for implementation of PeopleSoft ELM
- Conducted PeopleSoft HCM training sessions.

**2019 NAEP Educational Data Mining Competition** - The goal of the competition was to engage leading researchers and promising doctoral students to push the field of educational data mining forward, develop metrics for measuring students' test-taking activities, and help develop and test evaluation methods for educational analysis. Developed a classification model using random forest algorithm and successfully completed the competition with

35% prediction accuracy.

## https://sites.google.com/view/dataminingcompetition2019/winners

**Student Dropout Prediction** Challenge (In Class Kaggle Prediction Competition) – The objective of this competition was to accurately predict whether a student will drop out or not from the enrolled coursework. Completed this competition with 97% prediction accuracy.

https://www.kaggle.com/c/student-dropout/leaderboard

**Smart Tutoring system using Google BERT** - The purpose of this project is to create a virtual teaching assistant system in the field of financial literacy domain. This tutoring system presents some questions to the students, evaluates the answers by students, gives suggestions and assess the overall student's understanding of the topic. Used Google's NLP engine – BERT for creating question answering and evaluation system. This project is still being researched and in development phase.

## **EDUCATION**

New Jersey City University (School of Business)

Masters of Science

Jersey City NJ (USA)

Graduation: Dec 2019

Business Analytics and Data Science CGPA: 4.00

RTMNU Nagpur Nagpur, MH (India)
Bachelors of Engineering Graduation: Jun 2012

Electronics and Telecommunication CGPA: 3.65

## **CERTIFICATION**

Coursera Introduction to Big Data

IBM Big Data Foundation – Level 1

Stanford SQL

Udemy Mastering visualization using d3.js

## **LANGUAGES**

Fluent in English, Hindi and Marathi language(s)